<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2. Bootstrap on AWS Demos</title><link>/020_bootstrap/</link><description>Recent content in 2. Bootstrap on AWS Demos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/020_bootstrap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bootstrap Purpose</title><link>/020_bootstrap/021_bootstrap_purpose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/020_bootstrap/021_bootstrap_purpose/</guid><description>Demo: Bootstrap an AWS CDK Environment Why would use use the AWS CDK? To automate resource deployment in the AWS cloud.
We start each demonstration with a slide deck presenting the purpose of the demonstration. The bootstrap demo is no different!
Here are the purpose points for the bootstrap deck.
Why? I want to automate resource deployment in the AWS cloud. What? Create an AWS CDK environment. Where? In my AWS account.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrap Steps</title><link>/020_bootstrap/022_bootstrap_steps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/020_bootstrap/022_bootstrap_steps/</guid><description>Use AWS Cloud Shell for AWS CDK Purpose: Create an AWS CDK environment. Steps:
Sign into your AWS account. Launch AWS CloudShell. Confirm tools for AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK). Bootstrap AWS account for CDK. Deploy, destroy, repeat.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrap Script</title><link>/020_bootstrap/023_bootstrap_script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/020_bootstrap/023_bootstrap_script/</guid><description>Bootstrap AWS CDK If you simply use the command:
cdk bootstrap in an unbootstrapped environment, you would likely receive an error such as:
Specify an environment name like &amp;lsquo;aws://123456789012/us-east-1&amp;rsquo;, or run in a directory with &amp;lsquo;cdk.json&amp;rsquo;.
Environment = Account + Region A CDK environment consists of an AWS account + AWS region which you have bootstrapped to allow using the CDK to deploy resources.
graph TB subgraph env[CDK Environment] account((AWS Account)) region((AWS Region)) end Therefore, you could provide the cdk bootstrap command with the path of the environment in which you wish to deploy resources.</description></item><item><title>Unbootstrap Steps</title><link>/020_bootstrap/027_unbootstrap_steps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/020_bootstrap/027_unbootstrap_steps/</guid><description>Remove CDK bootstrap Purpose: Remove CDK environment if no longer needed.
If you no longer need to manage resources with the AWS CDK in an environment, you can &amp;ldquo;unbootstrap&amp;rdquo; that environment.
This effectively removes the CDK bootstrap
These are the high-level steps:
Remove CDKToolkit stack with CloudFormation. Remove CDK bootstrap bucket.</description></item><item><title>Unbootstrap Script</title><link>/020_bootstrap/028_unbootstrap_script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/020_bootstrap/028_unbootstrap_script/</guid><description>Unbootstrap AWS CDK Here is an example script to accomplish the removal of a CDK bootstrap.
In AWS CloudShell, perform the following commands. aws cloudformation list-stacks --query &amp;#34;StackSummaries[?StackName==&amp;#39;CDKToolkit&amp;#39;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;StackStatus==&amp;#39;CREATE_COMPLETE&amp;#39;]&amp;#34; aws cloudformation delete-stack --stack-name CDKToolkit cdkbucket=$(aws s3 ls | grep cdk- | awk &amp;#39;{printf $3}&amp;#39;) echo $cdkbucket aws s3api delete-objects --bucket $cdkbucket \ --delete &amp;#34;$(aws s3api list-object-versions \ --bucket $cdkbucket \ --output=json \ --query=&amp;#39;{Objects: Versions[].{Key:Key,VersionId:VersionId}}&amp;#39;)&amp;#34; aws s3api delete-bucket --bucket $cdkbucket If there are no versions of objects in the bucket to delete, you may receive an error on the delete-objects step.</description></item><item><title>Extra: Bootstrapping</title><link>/020_bootstrap/029_bootstrap_scratch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/020_bootstrap/029_bootstrap_scratch/</guid><description>Longer version of CDK Bootstrap Here is a video of a longer version of the CDK Bootstrap demonstration.
Notes:
Sign in to the AWS account you wish to use. Choose the AWS region in which you want to deploy and manage resources. Check node, npm, cdk software installation. Compose the environment path from the account id and region code. This longer video includes references to the awsdemo repo artifacts:
deck.md cdk-bootstrap.</description></item></channel></rss>